# Uchendu Uchendu

301-758-5070 | uxu5008@psu.edu | https://github.com/Uche6

# Software Developer / Front-end Developer

# About Me

I am an Informatics M.S. student at Pennsylvania State University. My interests are in Software Development and UI/UX Design. My current research is in Human-Computer Interaction. I have experience creating apps and interfaces with React and Flutter.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Pennsylvania State University

Master of Science in Informatics

University of Maryland Baltimore County

Bachelor of Science in Information Systems

State College, PA

Aug. 2020 - May 2022

Catonsville, MD

June 2015 - May 2020

# ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS AND AWARDS

CRA IDEALS Workshop Student Scholarship

March 2022

Louis Stokes Alliance Minority Participation (LSAMP)

June 2019 – May 2020

High Performance Computing NSF funding (REU Project)

Aug. 2019 - May 2020

# SKILLS

Programming Languages: Dart, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, PHP, Java, SwiftUI, Python, SQL

Developer Tools: Flutter, Node.js, React.js, Firebase, Angular, Bootstrap, Docker, Git, Xcode, VS Code, PyCharm,

IntelliJ, Eclipse

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows, MacOS Libraries: pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, XGBoost

Clusters: Taki, Hadoop

# Projects

# Effects of Micro Benefits of collective Organizations on Gig-Platform workers.

Aug. 2020 – Present

- Working in accordance with the Independent Drivers Guild to provide a micro-service to gig-platform workers.
- Created a application using Flutter for gig-platform workers.
- Studying the effects of Group Efficacy in a platform that promotes human agency.

#### Mobile Application for Stroke Prediction

Spring 2021

- Analyzed and utilized different stroke prediction techniques.
- Calculated and compared precision and accuracy scores.
- Created an interface for the mobile application using Adobe XD.

#### Covid-19 Geo-Map Visualization

Spring 2021

- Constructed an interactive Geo-Map display using Covid-19 data.
- Utilized Python and HTML to facilitate this visualization.

## Spam Detection using Machine Learning

Spring 2021

- Created a Spam detection model with 99% accuracy.
- Utilized the Multinomial Naive-Bayes classifier.

- Kroiz, G. C., Basalyga, J. N., **Uchendu, U.**, Majumder, R., Barajas, C. A., Gobbert, M. K., Markert, K., Mehta, A. and Neerchal, N. K. (2020). Stochastic precipitation generation for the Potomac river basin using hidden Markov models. UMBC Physics Department.
- Presented at the Mid-Atlantic Writing Center Association (MAWCA) (2020) research conference.
- Poster Presentation at the 27th UMBC McNair Research Conference (2019).
- Poster Presentation at the 3rd Annual University System of Maryland (USM) LSAMP Fall Research Symposium (2019).

#### EXPERIENCE

### Teaching Assistant

Aug. 2020 – present

College of Information Science and Technology

State College, PA

- Assisted in grading assignments
- Met with students to clarify the course material
- Presented material in class

### Undergraduate Research Assistant

Sept. 2019 – May 2020

Catonsville, MD

University of Maryland Baltimore County

- Applied the knowledge and skills of high-performance computing (HPC) and Big Data to solve challenges in Atmospheric Sciences.
- Utilized the UMBC data cluster system (HDFS and SPARK)

# Undergraduate Research Assistant

Summer 2019

University of Maryland Baltimore County

Catonsville, MD

- Conducted research that involved predicting future climate conditions by determining the cause-effect relationships between climate datasets.
- Developed regression models in Python using Xgboost
- Discovered non-linear causal relationships between datasets using Xgboost

# Writing Tutor

Sept. 2019 – May 2020

Catonsville, MD

- $UMBC\ Academic\ Success\ Center$ 
  - Assisted Students with help regarding writing assignments
  - Improved my writing skills
  - Presented at MAWCA2020 research that was done in the writing center (Importance of Diversity in the Writing Center)